[Music]
foreign
this is Ravi welcome to Tyson distask
automation tutorial
so this is our lesson 2 where I'm gonna
teach you the navigation of the Tasker
16. so basically in the tri-centives
Tasker what are all the different
options that are available and what are
all the different ribbons that are
available and what are all the different
pairs that are available I'm gonna teach
you how to navigate them and how to
analyze your Tasker UI okay
and then we will start
learning other automation Concepts okay
so now for this session we'll stick on
to the navigation of the task as 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
okay so with this lesson
you will be able to steer the navigation
and working pains in Tosca
and also you can recognize and manage
key task or sections
and you'll learn how to save undo redo
your work
if you see on the screen
the default view of Tasker so on the
screen you can see a default viewers
view of Tasker if you see
far left there is a section which is a
navigation pane
keep the overview of your work
and then right side in the middle there
is a working pane where you will be
working on some individual items of your
work and then you have another top
ribbon where you have different sections
test cases modules requirements and
execution right all these are our
different sections and also you have on
top ribbon there is Home Project view
test cases menu right so you have that
menu also so basically all these
sections I'm going to explain you
in this session so now let's jump onto
the system
and see the navigation of your present
taskbar
okay so this is my latest uh price and
test Tasker okay so this has the Tasker
has around four main sections
the first one is this is your left side
pane which is called as a navigation
pane where you can see the overview of
your work okay your overview of your
work
and the next one is this right side
middle pin right this one this is called
working pane where you'll be managing
your individual items okay
on which you are working on so you'll be
managing your work at individual item
level okay so this is another big
and the next one is if you see these are
the column headers
for your working pin
okay so these column headers can be
added
are removed
based on your requirement okay how you
just need to right click on your
column and click on column chooser
and then you have these many different
columns okay let's assume I want to add
a column called condition you just need
to double click on this
so this will add a new column here
if you want to remove this column just
you have to
click on this condition and drag
and drop when you see the cross mark
that will remove your color
okay and then there is another section
this one these are all the different
tabs that are available right
these are the different sections that
are available in Tasker so what are all
the
main sections that are available in
Tasker one is test cases modules
execution requirements test case design
issues configurations test planning okay
but for us I'm going to concentrate on
only first four different sections okay
test cases modules execution and
requirements
test cases
now let me first tell you what is
modules okay the module section where
you will be maintaining your technical
stuff of your system under test what do
you mean by that
the modules where you'll be storing your
elements and the element locators of
your system under test it's a kind of
object repository but more advanced
object repository when you compare to
compare with other automation tools okay
and then what is test cases so test
cases where you will be managing your
input values so basically the modules
are
your objects and object locators and the
business logic and the test data that
you will be supplying supplying and
managing under test cases folder okay
and also the flow of your test case will
be managed under test cases
and then what is execution so execution
means where you will be able to execute
your test cases and see the reports
right so this is where you'll be
executing your test cases
and then requirements section so this
requirement section where you can manage
your business requirements and tie your
test cases and execution
suits basically your test Suites and
your test cases you can map them to your
corresponding requirements so that it
gives you the traceability whenever you
execute your test cases okay so
basically you can track your entire
project
status
what is the completed percentage what is
the execution State what is the coverage
of your requirements right you can
manage all the requirements and then you
can tie your test cases and execution
test Suites
to your requirements
okay so these four are the main modules
that we are going to concentrate on
these sessions okay
hope you all understand the concepts let
me also cover some more topics okay so
how can you manage these sections how
can you manage these sections so let's
say if I want to bring requirements
section
okay to right side pin basically as a
right side tab all you need to do is
click on requirements track and
come to your middle of the pane
so if you want to place on top as a
requirement you can place here left you
can place here bottom you can place here
right if you want to place you can just
drag and drop here see the requirement
section is on the right side
okay there is another way how can you
open these sections
if you go to sections you can just click
on this execution you can simply open
your section as a floating
okay and also if you want to arrange
these requirements or tabs you can just
right click here either you can close
this section
or close all but this or you can float
this section or currently New Vertical
tab group you can make it as right see
it's a new vertical tab if I want to
make it as move to the next tab group I
can move the next crap group right all
these kind of so basically you can
arrange your sections
in this manner drag and drop also you
can do okay
and there is
if you want to create these sections on
your own
you just need to go to your project
on top ribbon
right under project right click
and then create a component folder right
project
and then under this project component
folder you can again create your own
modules folder
example and then you can create your
test case folder
execution folder requirements folder
right so this way you can create your
own sections also
okay
and then
hope I think I have covered okay let me
also tell you one more thing so if you
see on top here right this is to save
your workspace whatever the work you do
you are doing right and this is
undo your work and this is to redo your
work so undo and redo Works only if you
don't save your work right undo and redo
can be used if you have not saved your
work once you save your work you cannot
use your undo and redo sections on top I
am showing okay
hope you all understand the concepts of
how to navigate
in your latest Tasker 16 version okay
how can you navigate to
within the different panes how can you
navigate uh different sections how can
you navigate your top ribbon how can you
navigate to perform undo and redo and
save okay hope you all understand these
Concepts if you have any queries uh you
can leave your queries in the comment
box I'll try to respond to your queries
thank you
hope you all understand the concepts of
navigation of treasonous Tasker
16 version
so if you have any queries please leave
your comments in the comment box I'll
try to respond
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever more videos thank
you
[Music]